[music]
>> Welcome to what's new in the Payables
agent in Business Central in the 2026
release wave one. In this video, we'll
cover these cool additions we've been
working on for this release. We're super
excited about this. Let's get started.
The Payables agent now supports
one-to-one matching between invoice
lines and purchase order lines. It uses
AI to interpret line descriptions and
find the best match among your open
purchase orders.
When a match is found, the agent checks
if the received quantity is sufficient
for invoicing and highlights a warning
if it's not.
Receipt must still be done manually for
now.
A cornerstone page finance teams must
know about is the inbound e-documents
list.
This is where new draft invoices land,
and it now includes more information to
support these teams, giving them an
option to navigate to the agent tasks
for the specific invoice. Also, to
support finance teams working in the
same mailbox as the agent, they can now
see which emails have been processed and
avoid the risk of duplicate work.
Let's talk about cost.
The agent is free to try up to a certain
number of invoices. After that, you pay
based on volume using Copilot credits.
Here's how it works. 50 credits for the
invoice document plus five credits per
invoice line. So, a five-line invoice
costs 75 credits. At roughly 1 US cent
per credit, that's about 75 cents per
invoice.
Try using analysis assist on the posted
purchase invoice lines page to find the
invoice volume and the average number of
purchase invoice lines your company.
This will help you calculate the
projected cost of using the agent.
The Payables agent should be even easier
to discover. We are making it much
easier to try out the agent via the
agent configuration page, but we are
also surfacing the agent in familiar
places like the purchase invoice page
and purchase invoice list. These allow
accounts payable users to try out the
agent for free and process a single
invoice they upload without needing to
set up a shared mailbox or fully
activate the agent first.
We're excited to announce that the
Payables agent is now available in all
the countries and regions where Business
Central is available and is supported in
all the languages we as Microsoft
provide as part of our localizations.
For details, visit
aka.ms/bccopilotagentsavailability.
We'd love your feedback on the Payables
agent so we can make it even better.
Submit it directly from the purchase
document draft page using the provide
feedback action. You can include context
about the current invoice and follow our
replies on the feedback portal. Find the
feedback portal at
feedbackportal.microsoft.com
and make sure to view my feedback.
That's it for the news about the
Payables agent in this release wave.
Notice that some of these features may
not necessarily be part of the major
release, but will be available in an
upcoming minor release.
Now, over to Soren, our product manager
for the Payables agent.
On behalf of the Payables agent team,
thank you for watching this video.
Please keep the feedback coming so we
can keep improving on the agent.
Thank you for watching.
Hey, before you go, we want to make sure
you know about our YouTube channel, your
one-stop shop for skilling up on
Business Central. Bookmark it now if you
haven't already.